Joseph Cooper

Location: North Tyneside
cooper.joseph@gmail.com
https://github.com/grodin
+44 (0)7584 660151

Profile

I am a self-taught programmer, passionate about software engineering and enthusiastic about making a difference to people's lives. My natural critical thinking skills and precise communication abilities have been refined and strengthened by my education and work in mathematics. I have excellent interpersonal and organizational skills, gained and improved through my broad employment and wider life experience.

I am particularly engaged with producing correct, understandable, clean and secure code in collaboration with others. I enjoy following developments in software maintainability by contributing to open source, discussion with more experienced developers, and extensive reading.

Technical Skills

iccillical Skill	3				
TypeScriptPostgreSQLgLaTeXHaskell	eact/Vue it/mercurial	FireBaseRust		KotlinGradleAndroid development	
Projects & Op	en source	e contr	ibutions		
 Gratitude Journal w Mental health/we Local-first design, TypeScript 	llbeing tool to a	_	•	s Cl	
ktfmt				,	
Kotlin code formaImproved usabilitFixed several critic	y/maintainabili	-	9		
DWP Abbreviation	quick find we	b app			
	•		ning of DWP abbre	viations (over 2000 in regular	
used by DWP empWeb frontend	oloyees, speedi 。Rust			changes GolitHub Actions CI/CD	
Audio book player v	web app				
 Cross-platform audio book app to help children sleep 					
 Supports wide range of browsers and versions 					
Java/Kotlin + SprinDeploys via Docke	g Boot backen			Script + React.js frontend	
Android librarian a	pp for paper i	maps			
 Helps to plan out are already owner 	door trips by q		ing maps for geog	raphical area, showing which	
Works both offlingKotlin/JavaFir		aackond	Tost suite on (Cit Hub Actions Cl	
-	=	Jackenu	o rest suite on t	SILHUD ACTIONS CI	
Weekly task review		. + <i>E</i> 4			
Adds tasks complMicroserviceKOther open source	Kotlin + http4k	o uses rem		n and Wordpress REST APIs	
o kotest – Kotlin tes			o kotlin-result -	- Kotlin Result type	
RxBinding – RxJava) I ⁻ -	

Education & Qualifications	2024
Algorithms, Part 1 – Princeton University via Coursera	2021
FP101x: Introduction to Functional Programming – TU Delft via edX Master of Mathematics (MMath) – University of Newcastle	2014 2008
	2006
Employment History	
Administrative Officer – DWP, Retirement Services Directorate Responsibilities:	2022 – present
 processing changes of details for State Pension customers responding to State Pension customer inquiries received via post accurate communication of work done and in progress Skills: 	
 asynchronous team communication in hybrid working environment working/communicating with many teams across Retirement Services experience of DWP software (e.g. Searchlight, GYSP, PSCS, PTP CAM) 	
Volunteer bike mechanic – Recyke y'Bike, Byker, Newcastle Upon Tyne Responsibilities:	2020 – 2022
 refurbishing donated bikes for sale or giving to disadvantaged people accurate and comprehensive communication of in progress work maintenance of workshop and tools 	
 breaking down of unsalvagable bikes into recyclable and scrappable parts Skills: 	
solving problems with limited resourcesteaching less experienced colleagues	
organization of working environment	
English Language Teacher – The Dawson Group Italia, Parma, Italy Educom GmbH, Salzburg, Austria	2015 - 2017 2012 - 2014
Responsibilities: teaching English to professionals in industry	
 teaching English to small groups of private students 	
accurately assessing existing skills and needs of students	
 providing curricula to meet the needs of students Skills: 	
o inter-language, cross-cultural communication	
 time management, making best use of lesson time 	
Postgraduate Mathematics researcher – Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh Responsibilities:	2008 – 2012
 conducting original research in mathematics communicating research progress and results to mathematical community organizing weekly postgraduate research presentation sessions Skills: 	
o conducting research	
self-organizationwriting for an expert audience	
 presenting technical material 	
o analytical reasoning	